Yakubu M. Hassan

Frontend Developer

House No.25 Ajayi Crowther Street, Asokoro. Abuja, NIgeria

Phone No: 09033872114 Email: Yakubuh56@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yakubu-hassan/

Github: https://github.com/yarcx

PROFILE SUMMARY

A passionate Front-end Developer. A Javascript enthusiast, with passion for improving the human living experience through technology, with emphasis on aesthetics, efficiency, and security. When I'm not learning new technology as an afficionado of soccer, I spend my time on soccer video Games. Currently available for freelance work or hire.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3(Tailwind, Bootstrap, Chakra Ui, Material Ui, Sass, Ant Design, Styled Component)
- Javascript(Vue, Vuex, Vue CLI, Nuxt.js, React, React Native, Redux, Gatsby.js, Next.js), Typescript, Node, Express.
- Other Tools (Glt, Github, BitBucket, jira, Firebase)

EXPERIENCE

Cura Assistant Gmbh, Frankfurt, Germany. Frontend Developer

May 2021- Present

Built and streamlined existing code to improve site performance for entire company, Utilized cutting-edge JavaScript and HTML 5 techniques, frameworks, and libraries., Vue, Vuex, Nuxt, Vue CLI, React, Next, Redux, Firebase, Material Ui, Chakra, Tailwind, and Git.

Quicktell Solution, Minna. Frontend Developer

january 2020- March 2021

Working as a frontend engineer with a team of passionate developers to build functional and attractive digital environments for our company and its clients with different tools like, React, Redux, Next, TypeScript, GraphQL, Rest Api, Material Ui, Chakra, Tailwind, Git, and Clickup

Liverite HealthCare, Abuja- Frontend Developer

September 2020- January 2020

Responsible for building and deploying interactive web application using different frontend technologies. While also developing the client facing user interfaces of the team's Health Startup. Worked with tools like Vue, Vuex Nuxt, React, Redux Material Ui, tailwind, and Git.

Devcareers, Abuja-Frontend Developer

August 2020 - November 2020

- Worked with the amazing frontend development team using HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Javascript, Tailwind, Chakra UI, React, Redux, Git, and Github
- Also contributed to Open source projects and got better knowledge of GIT version control while at it.
- Lead a frontend team through the implementation of multiple projects, translating the figma designs into responsive and high quality web pages as well as testing through to deployment.

Loyola senior College , Ibadan - *Further Mathematics Teacher* April 2018 - April 2019

 Taught and Used tests, quizzes and other assignments to gauge students' learning and Documented attendance, assignments, grades and participation for students. Assessed student learning progress and comprehension with routine tests and standardized examinations.

EDUCATION

Ibrahim Badamassi Babangida University, Lapai Niger State - Degree

April 2013 - November 20

Bsc.Mathematics Science

Hobbies

Reading, Research, video games(Flfa) and Working out(exercise)